I love infographics.
私はインフォグラフィックが好きで
As an information designer,
情報デザイナーとして
I've worked with all sorts of data over the past 25 years.
25年以上にわたり 様々なデータを扱ってきました
I have a few insights to share, but first: a little history. NOTE Paragraph
詳しいお話をする前に 簡単な歴史をご紹介します NOTE Paragraph
Communication is the encoding, transmission and decoding of information.
情報伝達とは 情報の符号化・送信・復号です
Breakthroughs in communication mark turning points in human culture.
情報伝達の飛躍的進歩により 人類の文化は大きな転換点を迎えました
Oracy, literacy and numeracy were great developments in communication.
声、文字、数字による表現能力の獲得で 情報伝達は大きく進歩しました
They allow us to encode ideas into words
それにより 思考を言語で表すことができますし
and quantities into numbers.
量を数字で表すこともできます
Without communication, we'd still be stuck in the Stone Ages. NOTE Paragraph
情報伝達がなければ 人類は未だに石器時代でしょう NOTE Paragraph
Although humans have been around for a quarter million years,
人類の歴史は約25万年ですが
Nearly 3,000 years later, the first proper writing systems took shape. NOTE Paragraph
その約３千年後に 書記体系ができました NOTE Paragraph
Maps have been around for millennia and diagrams for hundreds of years,
地図は１千年前 ダイヤグラムは数百年前からあり
but representing quantities through graphics
グラフを使った量の表現は
is a relatively new development.
さらに最近の出来事です
It wasn't until 1786 that William Playfair invented the first bar chart,
1786年にようやく ウィリアム・プレイフェアが棒グラフを発明し
giving birth to visual display of quantitative information.
数量情報の視覚的な表現が始まりました
Fifteen years later, he introduced the first pie and area charts.
15年後 彼は 円グラフと面グラフも発明しました
His inventions are still the most commonly used chart forms today.
彼の発明は今日でも 最も広く使われています
Florence Nightingale invented the coxcomb in 1857
1857年 フローレンス・ナイチンゲールが 鶏頭図を発明しました
for a presentation to Queen Victoria on troop mortality.
ヴィクトリア女王に兵士の死因について 説明するためです
Highlighted in blue,
青で強調することで
she showed how most troops' deaths could have been prevented.
いかに兵士の死のほとんどが避けられたか 説明しています
Shortly after, Charles Minard charted Napoleon's march on Moscow,
すぐ後にチャールズ・ミナードが ナポレオン軍のモスクワ侵攻での兵力を図にし
illustrating how an army of 422,000 dwindled to just 10,000
422,000人から10,000人に 軍隊が減少する様子を
as battles, geography and freezing temperatures took their toll.
犠牲の原因となった戦闘、地形 低い気温との関連と共に示しています
He combined a Sankey diagram with cartography
サンキー・ダイアグラムと地図製作法を 組み合わせていて
and a line chart for temperature. NOTE Paragraph
折れ線グラフは気温です NOTE Paragraph
I get excited when I get lots of data to play with,
データを手に入れると興奮します
especially when it yields an interesting chart form.
特に面白いグラフになる場合です
Here, Nightingale's coxcomb was the inspiration
こちらは ナイチンゲールの鶏頭図に 着想を得て
to organize data on thousands of federal energy subsidies,
何千もの連邦政府のエネルギー助成金の データをまとめ
scrutinizing the lack of investment in renewables over fossil fuels.
化石燃料と比べて再生可能エネルギーへの 投資が不足していることを表しています
This Sankey diagram illustrates the flow of energy through the US economy,
こちらは サンキー・ダイアグラムで示した アメリカ経済におけるエネルギー消費の流れで
emphasizing how nearly half of the energy used is lost as waste heat. NOTE Paragraph
ほぼ半分は廃熱となり 失われていることを強調しました NOTE Paragraph
I love it when data can be sculpted into beautiful shapes.
美しい形に表されたデータが大好きです
Here, the personal and professional connections of the women of Silicon Valley
これはシリコンバレーの女性の 個人的または仕事上の繋がりです
can be woven into arcs,
円弧で表現できます
same as the collaboration of inventors birthing patents across the globe
世界で特許を生み出している 発明家同士の関係も同様にして
can be mapped. NOTE Paragraph
地図に描けます NOTE Paragraph
I've even made charts for me.
自分用のグラフまで作りました
I'm a numbers person, so I rarely win at Scrabble.
数字ばかり扱う私は 単語ゲーム「スクラブル」が苦手で
I made this diagram to remember all the two- and three-letter words
ゲームの公式辞書にある ２文字と３文字の単語をすべて覚えるため
in the official Scrabble dictionary. NOTE Paragraph
グラフにまとめました NOTE Paragraph
(Laughter)
（笑）
(Laughter)
（笑）
Sometimes I produce code to quickly generate graphics
何千ものデータ点から 素早くグラフを描けるように
from thousands of data points.
プログラムを書くこともあります
Coding also enables me to produce interactive graphics.
プログラムによって インタラクティブなグラフも作れます
Now we can navigate information on our own terms. NOTE Paragraph
自分の思うがままに 情報を操作することができるのです NOTE Paragraph
Exotic chart forms certainly look cool,
派手なグラフは確かにかっこいいです
but something as simple as a little dot may be all you need
しかし １つの小さな点のような シンプルなものだけで
to solve a particular thinking task.
理解できることもあります
In 2006, the "New York Times" redesigned their "Markets" section,
2006年『ニューヨーク・タイムズ』は 株式市場の欄をデザインし直しました
cutting it down from eight pages of stock listings
８ページにおよぶ株式一覧表を
to just one and a half pages of essential market data.
重要な市場データをまとめた １ページ半に削りました
We listed performance metrics for the most common stocks,
最も一般的な株式銘柄の 業績指標を一覧にしました
but I wanted to help investors see how the stocks are doing.
しかし 私は株式の動きを 投資家にわかるようにしたかった
So I added a simple little dot
だからシンプルな小さい点を 表に書き加えました
to show the current price relative to its one-year range.
過去１年間の変動幅に対する 現在の株価の位置づけを示しました
At a glance, value investors can pick out stocks trading near their lows
これで 底値に近い値段の株が すぐにわかります
by looking for dots to the left.
点が左側にあるものがそうです
Momentum investors can find stocks on an upward trajectory
値段が上昇している株もすぐにわかります
via dots to the right.
点が右側にあるものです
Shortly after, the "Wall Street Journal" copied the design. NOTE Paragraph
『ウォール・ストリート・ジャーナル』が すぐに真似しました NOTE Paragraph
Simplicity is often the goal for most graphics,
シンプルなことが 多くの場合は最も良いです
but sometimes we need to embrace complexity
しかし時には複雑であることを受け入れ
and show large data sets in their full glory.
巨大なデータ群を全て見せる必要があります
Alec Gallup, the former chairman of the Gallup Organization,
ギャラップ社の前会長 アレック・ギャラップは
once handed me a very thick book.
かつて私に分厚い書類を手渡しました
It was his family's legacy:
彼の家族の遺産です
hundreds of pages covering six decades of presidential approval data.
何百ページにもわたる 60年間の大統領支持率のデータでした
I told him the entire book could be graphed on a single page.
私は彼に 全データを １ページの図にできると言いましたが
"Impossible," he said.
「無理だ」と彼は信じません
And here it is:
ご覧ください
25,000 data points on a single page.
25,000のデータ点が １ページにあります
At a glance, one sees that most presidents start with a high approval rating,
一目で ほとんどの大統領が 高い支持率でスタートするものの
but few keep it.
ほぼ維持できないとわかります
Events like wars initially boost approval;
戦争などの出来事は最初だけ 支持率を押し上げ
scandals trigger declines.
スキャンダルは支持率低下を招きます
These major events were annotated in the graphic but not in the book.
このグラフにある 重要な出来事の注釈は 元の書類にはないものです
The point is, graphics can transmit data with incredible efficiency. NOTE Paragraph
つまりグラフによって データは非常に理解しやすくなるのです NOTE Paragraph
Graphicacy --
グラフィカシーとは
the ability to read and write graphics --
グラフを読み取ったり描いたりする 技術のことですが
is still in its infancy.
それはまだ生まれたばかりです
New chart forms will emerge and specialized dialects will evolve.
新しいグラフの型が生まれ 専門的な表現が発達するでしょう
Graphics that help us think faster
グラフによって私たちの理解が早まり
or see a book's worth of information on a single page
本１冊分の情報をたった１ページで 見ることもできます
are the key to unlocking new discoveries.
グラフは 新しい発見をするうえで 重要な鍵となるでしょう
Our visual cortex was built to decode complex information
私たちの視覚野は複雑な情報を 復号するために作られていて
and is a master at pattern recognition.
パターン認識に長けています
Graphicacy enables us to harness our built-in GPU
グラフィカシーによって 私たちは脳内のＧＰＵを活用でき
to process mountains of data
山のようなデータを処理します
and find the veins of gold hiding within. NOTE Paragraph
そして隠された金脈を発見するのです NOTE Paragraph
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
(Applause and cheers)
（拍手）